

Michael

Backend Software Developer

12 December 1987



California



949-228-0695



to 6 (Expert).]

michael hor vath 87@gmail.com

About me –

Michael is basically a husky puppy that was trapped in a human's body and forced to write software. He enjoys climbing, running trails then napping, howling with his guitar, and anything else he can do outdoors. He's been coding for about five years now, but he's been exploring since the day he could walk – perhaps even earlier.

He views Elixir as "the one that got away" and would do anything for a second chance to show her how much he cares.

Python Whiteboarding VIM Linux Figuring it out CSS (*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness)

beliefs

Continual growth is key to enjoyment of life; challenge begets growth.

Passion is a must.

Software = Poetry + Math

education

2006-2011 B.A. cum laude

University of Kansas

Psychology and Statistics

2002-2006 High school, 4.0 GPA

Shawnee Mission East HS

Extras: Diving, Soccer, Choir, Science Olympics

awards

1997	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
1998	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
1999	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
2000	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
2001	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
2005	Science Olympiad State Champion, Chemistry
2006	CalTech Signature Award, Excellence in Science and Mathematics
2016	Heart and Soul Award, Lawrence Ultimate Frisbee League

experience

2018 - Now Software Engineer

Fluxergy, LLC

- Designed clinical test data system with real-time data-uploading and retrieval via Azure Webapp Services and Docker Containers.
- Responsible for requirements gathering, spec-writing, development and documentation of department agnostic shop-floor-control system.
- Refactored computer vision analysis pipelines for improved algorithm performance, increased modularity, and to allow for proper testability.

2017 - 2018 Software Engineer

Embrace Healthwear, LLC

Developed activity classification models with biometric data to map physical therapy research to procedural findings.

2016 - 2017 Personal Project

Elixir/Machine Learning

Built a neural net constructor in Elixir, in order to better understand the fundamentals of machine. Followed Gene Sher's "Handbook of Neuroevolution Through Erlang" and translated each project to Elixir.

skills

2018-2020 Python, Django, Flask, PHP, MySQL, Docker, LaTex, docker-compose, Git, Cloud resources (Azure and AWS), Database desgin, Elasticsearch and

Kibana, PowerBI, Javascript/HTML/CSS

2010-2020 Program evaluation, testing, requirements gathering, software design, technical liaison, public speaking, presentation, interviewing

other information

Michael used to work in construction and property management. He's found some odd overlap between his previous career and his current one, mostly in visualizing interdepent systems and the value of elbow grease (not to mention the horror of opening up someone else's beloved home to find that the whole thing is tied together with (more or less) strings). He'd love to find a home where he can continue to grow and be challenged by exciting new projects on a regular basis.